ARMANDO SANCHEZ

Los Angeles, Ca. · 213-880-2436

armandosanchez855@yahoo.com · www.linkedin.com/in/armando-sanchez-92b548229 ·

Portfolio: https://main.dsyf52c4veduj.amplifyapp.com/

MERN Stack Developer / React Developer with experience designing, developing, and testing web applications throughout the software development life cycle. As a self-learner, I can adapt to new things and take on new challenges. Comprehensive knowledge in MySQL, MongoDB, React, Express, Node.js., Bootstrap, etc. skillful in creating servers and databases for functionality and designing and developing API's. Deploy web applications on AWS and Render. Maintain Parent and Child elements by using State and Props in React. Passionate about learning new technologies and building web applications.

EXPERIENCE

2023 – PRESENT

FRONT-END DEVELOPER INTERN, THE STUDY SPOT

BUILDING A STARTUP COMPANY'S WEBSITE USED FOR TUTORING SERVICES. MAINTAINING AND DEVELOPING A RESPONSIVE WEB APPLICATION USING REACT, HTML, CSS, AND OTHER VARIOUS TECHNOLOGIES.

2017 - PRESENT

MACHINE OPERATOR, ACCURATE STEEL HEAT TREATING/ION ACCURATE

Answer and respond to customer inquiries, requirements, and needs. Provide excellent service to customers. Verify documents and reports in accordance with the merchandise in shop. Perform and execute functions relating to merchandise preparation, staging and outbound shipments. Monitor all inventory orders, using the documented data on orders to analyze supply and demand and make inventory projections. Create purchase orders. Operate tasks as a machine operator (furnaces) and ability to read blueprints.

2015 - 2017

SALES ASSOCIATE/CUSTOMER SERVICE, UNDER ARMOUR INC.

Greeted customers, responded to questions, improved engagement with merchandise and provided outstanding customer service.

EDUCATION

JANUARY 2019

BACHELOR OF ARTS - SOCIOLOGY, CALIFORNIA STATE UNIVERISTY OF LOS ANGELES

HARD SKILLS

- Fast Learner
- Detail Oriented
- Bilingual Spanish & English
- Creative
- Persistent
- Driven
- Self-aware
- Fast-pace
- Developers Tool knowledge
- Motivated
- Time Management

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Git & Github
- Visual Studio Code
- MongoDB Atlas
- Node Package Manager (NPM)
- Deploying a website
- Creating a website
- Navigating the terminal
- AJAX/ APIs/ Axios
- Material UI Framework
- Framer Motion Framework
- Debugging knowledge
- Cross Origin Resource Sharing (CORS)
- JSON Web Token

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT CERTIFICATES

- Learn HTML Course (2021) Online Course- Codecademy
 - I first started my self-taught journey with this HTML course. I learned at its most basic level, HTML is used to structure web pages by defining elements such as headings, paragraphs, and links. As I advance in the HTML course I learned more complex elements like forms, tables, and multimedia to create interactive and visually appealing websites. The most advanced subject in HTML is likely to be its integration with other web technologies like CSS and JavaScript, which can be used to further enhance the user experience and functionality of a website.
- Lean CSS Course (2021) Online Course- Codecademy
 - The second course I learned was CSS. I learned that CSS is used to change the color, font, and size of text, as well as add backgrounds and borders to elements on a page. As I continued learning CSS, I learned to use more advanced layout techniques like flexbox and grid to create complex and responsive layouts. The most advanced subject in CSS is likely to be its integration with other web technologies like JavaScript, which can be used to create dynamic and interactive user interfaces. I picked learning also CSS frameworks like Bootstrap that provide pre-built components and styles to speed up the development process. Overall, CSS is a powerful tool for creating visually appealing and functional web pages.
- Learn SQL Course (2022) Online Course- Codecademy
 - The first database language I learned was SQL. Structured Query Language is a programming language used to manage and manipulate data in relational databases. At its most basic level, SQL is used to create, read, update, and delete data in tables using simple commands like SELECT, INSERT, UPDATE, and DELETE. As I continued learning SQL syntaxes, I learned more complex queries and statements to join tables,

filter, and aggregate data, and perform calculations. In this course I was able to use a Lyft database to create queries that would extract certain riders, trips, and cars.

• Learn Node.js Course (2022) - Online Course- Codecademy

o I learned Node.js because I had already taken the JavaScript course, and learning Node was convenient to me because I can use JavaScript Language in the backend. Node.js can be used to build simple web servers that respond to HTTP requests with static content. I am able to use frameworks like Express to build complex RESTful APIs. Node.js has a strong community of developers and a vast ecosystem of modules and libraries that make it a powerful and versatile tool for building scalable and high-performance applications. Overall, Node.js is a powerful tool for building modern web and network applications.

• Learn Bootstrap Course (2022) - Online Course- Codecademy

O I learned Bootstrap because it is a popular open-source front-end framework that provides pre-built components, styles, and JavaScript plugins for building responsive web page applications. I learned how to use basic styling and layout to HTML elements using its grid system and CSS classes. I have knowledge in React Bootstrap components, I have created Card, Carousels, and Form Components in my projects.

• Learn JavaScript Course (2022) - Online Course - Codecademy

o I learned JavaScript right after I learned HTML and CSS. I knew I must learn JavaScript to be able to create interactive and dynamic web applications. I learned what call-backfunctions are, conditional-statements, for-loops, switch-statements, objects, arrays, etc. I learned different array methods, how to create a variable, what the DOM tree is about, for me to create interactive web application. With JavaScript Syntaxes I was able to learn Node.js and React.js to build a powerful single page application.

• Learn React Course (2022) - Online Course - Codecademy

o React must be my favorite course that I learned in Codecademy. React allows developers to create large web applications that can change data, without reloading the page. React Components makes it simple for me to develop web-applications because I can pass components along my project. Breaking the code down and passing it along to other components in my project. I learned different types of hooks in the course that I use in my projects. The useEffect() hook allows me to fetch data from the backend, useState() allows me to change the states in my components, useNaviagate() to go to a different page, and I learned how to create my own custom hooks.

• Learn MongoDB Course (2022) - Online Course - Codecademy

O I learned MongoDB to complete the MERN Stack courses that I learned. MongoDB is a popular open-source NoSQL database that stores data in flexible, JSON-like documents instead of traditional rows and columns used in relational databases. At its most basic level, MongoDB can be used to create collections of documents and perform CRUD (Create, Read, Update, Delete) operations on those documents using simple queries.

• Connecting Front-End to Back-End Course (2022) - Online Course - Codecademy

o I learned how to connect the front-end to the back end in a MERN Stack project by creating RESTful API using Node.js and Express to handle requests from the frontend. I learned the CRUD Paradigm to perform API operations. I used Libraries like Axios to make the HTTP requests from the frontend to the backend API. I learned how to

implement user authentication and authorization using libraries like JSON Web Tokens(JWT). Allowing users to securely access protected routes in the backend API.

- Deploy a website using AWS (2022) -Online Course Codecademy
 - o I learned how to deploy a website to a cloud platform like AWS.
- React-Router Certificate (2023) Online Course Codecademy
 - o I learned React-Router to make my web applications more modern. I define routes for different pages or components in my React projects, allowing users to navigate between them using URLs. I learned how to use React-Router to better help a user find whatever it is they search in a query parameter using the useSearchParams() hook. I learned how to use Link and NavLinks to move from one page to another.
- <u>Learn Express Course (2022)</u> -Online Course Codecademy
 - O I learned how to create routes for handling HTTP requests and responses in this Express course. Setting up middleware for processing requests and serve static files. I used Express to perform authentication and authorization duties in my e-commerce project to handle the requests from the frontend. I learned how to use an open-source library tool like Morgan to return a middleware function.

Projects

- o MERN Stack Project | E-Commerce Website
 - https://github.com/asanc139/MERN Stack
 - https://mern-nostalgia-app.onrender.com/
 - This is my MERN Stack Project. It is an E-commerce store with the theme being Nostalgia. I made this project relevant to my childhood. I used MongoDB, Express, React, and Node.js. I created an atlas MongoDB database to store products, user-info, etc. I used Express to set my backend API routes for incoming requests from the frontend. I used React for the frontend UI along with React Bootstrap and Material UI. I used different hooks along my project as well as Axios whenever I used the useEffect hook to make a call to the backend. I installed Node.js to run JavaScript code on the backend server side. I deployed this project on Heroku.
- React Project | To Do List Website
 - https://github.com/asanc139/react.js
 - https://main.d3eekbora9qesv.amplifyapp.com/
 - This is my React To Do List project. I used different states in this project from useRef, useEffect, and useState. I used simple array methods to filter, remove, add, or update the current state the list is in.
- React Router Project | Pet's Adoption Website
 - o https://github.com/asanc139/Pets_React
 - https://main.d3fafmtkw6671z.amplifyapp.com/

This is a Pet's Adoption Website that allows users to view all the animals of a particular species and view the profiles of a specific animals. I added client-side routing in this React-Routing Project. I imported RouterProvider in the root folder and defined the attribute router with the value of appRouter. This is where I will transform a Route Component to a route object. To distinguish unique searches among different types of animals for my users, I created a URL parameter called :type to navigate to the proper animal they searched for, useEffect() hook, I passed type to our API's getPets method which fetches pets of thespecificed type to be rendered on the page. Along with the help of useParams() hook to help get the exact value from the query search.

HTML/CSS Project | Social Media Mockup Website

- o https://github.com/asanc139/asanc139.github.io2
- o https://asanc139.github.io/asanc139.github.io2/
 - This was my third project I ever made. I used just HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. I focused on structure and styling as I created a funny cartoon social media mock-up page for cartoon characters. I was comfortable with HTML and CSS, I felt like I had a good understanding on HTML and how to structure div's and creating class attributes to distinguish each div in this project so I can style that div or header or p tag in the CSS file. I was fairly new learning JavaScript at the time of building this project but I used event Listeners whenever a user would like a post, the heart shape image would appear on the liked image.

o JavaScript/HTML/CSS Game Project | Robot Game Website

- https://github.com/asanc139/asanc139.github.io3
- https://main.drrp210k5ofyy.amplifyapp.com/
 - In this Robot Game I made using JavaScript. A user would have three doors three options to choose and open. If the user clicked the door with the robot within the first two try's, the user loses the game. I used conditional statements to decide what happens when an event listener such as a button is being clicked, to determine the outcome of the game. As, well as Math.floor and Math.random to generate a random door in which the Robot will be behind.

o E-commerce Event Handler Project | E-commerce Website

- o https://github.com/asanc139/asanc139-github.io4
- https://main.d2kjznkf3ldo19.amplifyapp.com/
 - This is an e-commerce website that mainly focuses on JavaScript Document Object Model(DOM). DOM focuses on manipulating element parts from the HTML file, This project also focuses on

creating a handlebar expression with if block helpers along with each helper block.